# **MI ZHANG**

Yuzhong District, Chongqing, China (+86) 177-2308-1431

HomePage: https://zhangmmi.github.io/ zhangmmi@outlook.com

#### **PROFILE:**

I'm now a Master candidate in Institute of Life Sciences, Chongqing Medical University (CQMU), under the supervision of Prof. Chen Xu since September 2016. I had 8 months of research experience at the Molecular Biology Laboratory, College of Basic Medical Sciences, Shanghai Jiao Tong University (SJTU), under the supervision of Prof. Jing Yi (Lab PI) and Dr. Xueqing Sun from November 2017 to July 2018. Previously, I received my bachelor degree in CQMU in June, 2016.

#### **EDUCATION:**

## Master | Institute of Life Sciences, Chongqing Medical University

Sep 2016-Now

- Major in Sympathetic and Prostate Cancer
- Supervisor: Prof. Chen Xu

## **Bachelor** | Preventive Medicine, Chongqing Medical University

Sep 2011-Jun 2016

• Major in Preventive Medicine

#### **RESEARCH INTERESTS:**

Sympathetic and Prostate Cancer

#### **PUBLICATIONS:**

- Qing-Qing Yin, Lin-Hui Xu, Mi Zhang, Chen Xu, Muscarinic acetylcholine receptor M1
  mediates prostate cancer cell migration and invasion through hedgehog signaling Asian
  Journal of Andrology, 20, 1-7, 2018.
- ZHANG Rui-yuan, LIU Qin, GUO Rui-xi, **Mi Zhang**, Qinchun Chen, *Cognition, attitude towards funeral directors and their influencing factors among occupational populations* Chinese Journal Of Public Health (中国公共卫生), 33(1): 117-121, 2017.

### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:**

Research Intern, Molecular Biology Laboratory, SJTU

Nov 2017-Jul 2018

- Topic: Effect of beta2 adrenergic receptor on prostate cancer metastasis and its mechanism.
- Supervisor: Prof. Jing Yi and Dr. Xueqing Sun.

**Professional Intern**, The Center for Disease Control and Prevention, Chongqing, China Nov 2015-May 2016

- Topic 1: Investigation of tuberculosis patients.
- Topic 2: The propaganda and education of health and health knowledge for primary and middle school students.

**Professional Intern**, The Second People's Hospital of Banan District, Chongqing, China Jul 2015-Nov 2015

• Topic: Operation observation and practice; Collation of the survey data of elderly and mental patients.

Social Practice, The College Students' Summer Social Practice

Aug 2014-Sept 2014

• Topic: Questionnaire design, distribution and statistical analysis of funeral and interment work

Social Practice, The College Students' Summer Social Practice

Aug 2012-Sept 2012

Topic: A random interview on sex education for primary and middle school students.

# **MI ZHANG**

Yuzhong District, Chongqing, China (+86) 177-2308-1431

HomePage: https://zhangmmi.github.io/zhangmmi@outlook.com

# SCHOLARSHIPS AND AWARDS:

- 3rd prize, The 14th "Challenge Cup" National College Students Extracurricular Academic Competition of Chongqing Medical University (2015).
- 1st prize, The 13th "Challenge Cup" National College Students Extracurricular Academic Competition in Chongqing Medical University (2012).

# **QUALIFICATION CERTIFICATES:**

• Level 3, National Public Dietitian.

#### **ACTIVITIES:**

• Vice Minister of the editorial department of the college students' Association.